Let's learn how to do a forward and back hip slide with our shimmy.
So we're going to be layering this on top.
So we're going to have our feet slightly apart and first of all, my name is Karen and this is Johanna and we're with Hip Expressions Belly Dance Studio in St. Petersburg, Florida.
I'm going to turn to the side here because you're going to want to see how I move forward and back with this.
My hips are going to stay horizontal.
Feet are slightly apart.
Knees are bent.
Belly button pulled in and we're going to be sliding the hips forward and back.
So we're going to be pushing them slightly forward and pulling this in and back.
Now let's get our shimmy going now that you know how to do a nice strong shimmy.
This is how you're going to layer it.
You're going to forward and back and forward and back.
Forward and back.
Be sure to keep your chest lifted.
Keep your chin nice and raised.
Keep your shoulders relaxed.
Forward and back.
Forward and back and of course, depending on your music and the tempo, this is something you could do a little faster too.
So it's how you want to accent your music and make your shimmy look really special doing your forward and back sliding shimmy.